The fight was against the raiders... but the feud was between themselves!
Buck and the Preacher is a action, comedy, western
film directed by Sidney Poitier.
A wagon master and a con-man preacher help freed slaves
dogged by cheap-labor agents out West.
Buck, played by Sidney Poitier.
Preacher, played by Harry Belafonte.
Ruth, played by Ruby Dee.
Deshay, played by Cameron Mitchell.
Floyd, played by Denny Miller.
Madam Esther, played by Nita Talbot.
Buck and the Preacher is a 1972 American Western film released by Columbia
Pictures, written by Ernest Kinoy and directed by Sidney Poitier.
Poitier also stars in the film alongside Harry Belafonte and Ruby Dee.
This is the first film Sidney Poitier directed.
Vincent Canby of The New York Times said Poitier "showed a talent for easy,
unguarded, rambunctious humor missing from his more stately movies".
This film broke Hollywood Western traditions by casting black actors as central characters and portraying both
tension and solidarity between African Americans and Native Americans in the late 19th century.
The notable blues musicians Sonny Terry, Brownie McGhee, and Don Frank Brooks
performed in the film's soundtrack, composed by jazz great Benny Carter.
The film explores themes of con man, kansas, usa, preacher, wagon master, 1860s.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.